booksprout.co 2019-04-08

# Privacy Policy - Booksprout

Last updated: May 17, 2018

Book Sprout Services ("us", "we", or "our") operates the https://booksprout.co website and the Booksprout mobile application (the "Service").

This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use and disclosure of Personal Information when you use our Service. Our privacy commitment is to ensure the accuracy, confidentiality, and security of your Personal Information and to allow you to request access to, and correct your Personal Information as may be required.

**_Personal Information_**

"Personal Information" is information about an identifiable individual and may include your name, age, home address, phone number, marital status, income and financial information, education, employment information and identification numbers (such as your social insurance number).

**_Personal Information Collection and Use_**

We are committed to providing our clients, customers, members ("you", "your" or "them") with exceptional service. Providing the Service may involve the collection, use and, at times, the disclosure of your Personal Information. The Personal Information about you which we collect will be limited to that which is necessary for the purposes identified to you by us. Personal Information will be collected by us by fair and lawful means.

Whenever we collect Personal Information about you, we will explain how we intend to use the information. We will limit the information we collect to what we need for those purposes and we will use it only for the purposes described.

We obtain most of our information about you directly from you or through your interactions with the Service and any other organization with whom you provided your consent to disclose Personal Information to us.

We will only collect Personal Information that is necessary to provide the Service and to fulfill the following purposes:

  * To verify identity;
  * To identify your preferences in administering the Service;
  * To send you newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you;
  * To open and manage an account for the Service;
  * To ensure you receive a high standard of service;
  * To protect you and us from error, fraud and other illegal activities;
  * To respond to your questions and requests;
  * To provide you with electronic and other marketing communications with information and offers that may be of interest to you; and
  * To comply with legal and regulatory requirements and as otherwise required or permitted by applicable laws.

**_Consent to Use Personal Information_**

We will obtain your consent to collect, use or disclose Personal Information except as set out under applicable laws. Depending on the situation and the sensitivity of the information, we may obtain your consent in different ways. Consent may be obtained verbally, online through check-boxes or other means or directly from you in writing.

**_Withdrawing Consent_**

You may withdraw your consent at any time upon reasonable notice, subject to legal, regulatory or contractual requirements. Please note that withdrawing your consent may affect our ability to continue to provide you with the Services or certain functions within the Services that you have or would like to receive and which may be of value to you. To withdraw or change your consent, you may contact us or following the unsubscribe instructions in any message/communication at the address or telephone number listed at the end of this policy.

**_Who We Share Your Personal Information With_**

We will not share or sell your Personal Information to other parties unless consent has been provided or as otherwise set out herein.

There are some types of disclosure of your Personal Information which may occasionally occur without your consent as part of us fulfilling our routine obligations and/or conducting business in the ordinary course and in accordance with applicable laws. These situations include:

  * within our company and any controlled subsidiaries and affiliates;
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud or respond to a law enforcement request; and
  * as required or permitted by applicable law, such as in conjunction with a subpoena, government inquiry, litigation, dispute resolution or similar legal process (which may include lawful access by courts, law enforcement or governmental agencies).

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service, to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related activities or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used. These third parties have access to your Personal Information do not have an independent right to use the information and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose. As well, some service providers are subject to their own legal compliance requirements and the laws of their jurisdiction. Some service providers and their processing servers may be required to disclose information to courts, government authorities, regulators or law enforcement in accordance with applicable laws of that country. For more information on the manner in which our service providers treat your personal information, please contact us as set out at the end of this policy. 

Your Personal Information may be shared, stored or accessed in Canada or other jurisdictions or countries where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction. Your personal information may be disclosed in response to valid demands or requests from governments, regulators, courts and law enforcement authorities in those jurisdictions or countries. 

If you are located outside Canada and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the information, including Personal Information, to the USA for processing and use.

**_Retention of Personal Information_**

We will retain your Personal Information for the time it is required to meet the purposes set out above and for a reasonable length of time thereafter or to otherwise meet legal or regulatory requirements. Once your Personal Information is no longer required for such purposes, it will be destroyed, deleted or made anonymous.

**_Accuracy of Personal Information_**

We make all reasonable efforts to keep your Personal Information up-to-date and we endeavor to base our decisions on accurate and timely information when we make a determination that may impact you. We rely on you to disclose all material Personal Information to us and to inform us of any relevant changes, out-of-date, or incomplete information (for example, a name change or change in telephone number). If you discover any inaccurate information, please contact us and we will make the corrections and ensure this change of information is recorded. We want to ensure that the Service is not affected by incomplete or inaccurate Personal Information.

**_How We Ensure Security of Your Personal Information_**

The security of your Personal Information is important to us. We take precautions to protect your Personal information using commercially reasonable means. Your Personal Information is protected both online and offline, regardless the manner in which the information is submitted to us, with safeguards and security measures appropriate to the sensitivity of the Personal Information, such as using passwords, encryption, firewalls, restricted employee access or other methods.

**_Your Access To Personal Information_**

You have the right to access, update, and correct inaccuracies in your Personal Information in our custody and control, subject to certain exceptions prescribed by law. You may request access to your Personal Information and update or correct inaccuracies in the Personal Information we have in our custody or control or request that we delete your Personal Information by sending a written request to us at the contact information set out at the end of this policy.

Please note that we may request certain Personal Information for the purposes of verifying the identity of the individual seeking access to any Personal Information records. 

**_Cookies and Online Tracking Technology_**

We may use cookies, pixel tags, web beacons and other tracking technologies or log data on our websites, applications, email messages and advertisements to gather information about your visit (such as demographic data, browser type, device ID, IP address, pages visited, activities conducted on the page, and the day and time of your visit). When using a mobile device, we may collect information such as the type of mobile device you use, your mobile device unique ID, the IP address of your mobile device, your mobile operating system, the type of mobile Internet browser you use and other statistics.

Using cookies and other tracking technologies provides benefits to you, such as allowing you to maintain your account login information or contact information and other key elements relating to the Service between visits. In addition, we use information gathered from cookies to autofill fields on forms relating to the Service. This information can be corrected by you before submitting any form or inquiry or you can disable the cookie as discussed below and the information will not be collected.

To measure site activity, provide a better user experience, and tailor our marketing communications, we or our service providers or business partners may compile information from the cookies, pixel tags, web beacons or other tracking technologies on our websites and use third party services such as Google Analytics that collect, monitor and analyze this type of information in order to increase our Service's functionality. This information may be combined with other information collected online or offline about you, including data provided by third party sources, and may be used or shared for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

To the extent that Internet Protocol (IP) addresses or similar identifiers are considered Personal Information by local law, we treat these identifiers and associated information as Personal Information. Similarly, to the extent that non-personal information is combined with Personal Information, we treat the combined information as Personal Information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy.

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service. Please refer to your browser Help instructions to learn more about cookies and other technologies and how to manage their use. If you elect to refuse or delete cookies, you will need to repeat this process if you use another computer, or change browsers. If you choose to decline cookies, some of the functionality of our Service may be impaired.

**_Links To Third Party Websites_**

Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party's site. We have no control over, and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services and we strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.

**_Children's Privacy_**

We do not target or knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of majority. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your child has provided us with Personal Information, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Information from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

**_Changes To This Privacy Policy_**

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.

You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

**_How to Contact Us_**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us via our contact form.
